Claude is the world's number one design
agent for building beautiful websites.
But just because your site looks pretty
doesn't mean that it will sell or get
customers. For that, you need to use the
correct skills. And in this video, I'll
show you the most important ones across
seven levels so you can build beautiful
websites that are mobile optimized,
sound like they've been written by a
human, and have the correct structure
without the need to be a design expert.
So, if you haven't already, grab that
beautiful coffee and let's dive straight
in. So, level one is finding the
standard. Now, building a beautiful
website isn't actually the hard part.
It's the other stuff around it. And I'm
going to cover those seven skills here.
And by the end of the video, you will
know everything you need to know to
build websites that do actually sell or
just significantly level up your
website, including all the psychological
things that I've learned from doing this
myself that you're not going to want to
miss out. So, how do we find out what
the standard is? Well, we need a great
reference point. And one of the best
resources I found for this is going to
be referral.design. And I'm going to
timestamp everything down below. So, you
can go to any section you like to, but I
encourage you to watch every bit because
it's going to have stuff that you
probably haven't seen before. So, what I
would encourage you to do at level one
is effectively find a website in your
niche that is gold standard, that has
won awards, that is converting
customers. Now, if I come on to this
section here, the one that I'm going to
be using this one is going to be
Mintlify, which I think is a beautiful
and gorgeous website. As you can see,
it's got a nice background here. It
scrolls down, it shows you. Now, what
this has done is given us the design
DNA, the design blueprint such that we
can actually understand what makes this
design fantastic. And when we give that
to Claude, we can build a version for
ourselves. So, now we found a great
design, and it would be awesome for us
to have that. We're going to do
something that most people never do and
that's think about something beyond the
homepage because to have a great website
what we need is a full structure. So
there's a couple of ways to do this. You
can build the site and claude. One of
the cool tools that I've been using a
lot recently is something called Reloom.
Now Reloom is kind of like this really
decent. It's built by designers. It's
got loads of individual kind of like
design knowledge baked into it. But it's
very cool. Now with Reloom we can
actually get full site maps like this.
And this is what I want really. I want
to get a bird's eye view of my website
because if we're handing this over to a
client or building it ourselves, people
aren't just going to stay on the
homepage. They're going to click into
different things, right? We're going to
need a wireframe that explains what
everything looks like. We're going to
want some idea about what does design
look like, and we need to give it a
brief. And I found really to be the
fastest way to get this up and running.
You can do this in Claude if you want
to, but if you want to do it quicker,
you might find this very helpful. So,
there's two ways we can do this. Number
one with this skill at level two is you
can do export. So if you click on export
for example, what you can do is come
over, click on a new project and then
effectively you can describe it. So I
might say hey that I want you to build
for me a roofing company that is
bestin-class using the below design
principles. Then once you've done that
come down and literally just paste in
that URL that you grab from this website
right here and you can if you want to
also just copy and paste all of this and
just drop it in. Then once you've done
that you'll actually get a site map
that's generated from Room. And I think
this is really cool. Now, one of the
reasons why this is really handy is we
can actually move these sections up and
down. So, remember an ounce in print is
worth a pound in post. So, we're still
going to make this look amazing, but
what's great is that we can actually
think through what does our site map
look like? Will about us page, a
services page, projects, blog, contact
us, everything. We can look at the
wireframes, which is fantastic. And then
on the wireframe section, you can
actually just see what all of those
different things look like. We can move
them around. We can edit them in the
left hand side. It's really great to
spend a few minutes going through and
building out everything you want to. And
of course, we've got the style guide
based on everything that we gave. We've
got the colors, we've got things that we
can change. If we don't like seller, we
want to change something else. We can do
anything we want. So, it gives us this
allin-one platform effectively to kind
of build any website that we like. Then,
once you've got to a point where you're
really happy with the wireframes, what
we can do is come over to top right and
click on export. And you can export this
directly to Claude design, but for the
purpose of this, I'm going to export it
via HTML. And then you want to come back
over to Claude, upload that zip file and
say, "Hey, I want you to go ahead and
build for me a beautiful website using
this link based on the zip file and all
the design systems that we got from
Breloom. And what we can do is also grab
this reference link." So Claude's got
access to the original. And then you
want to go ahead and grab this design
loop skill. It will be the second link
in the description. Once you click on
that link, you will land on this page
here, which is where I keep all my free
resources. Again, it's 100% free. You
come in basically, and then you'll see
the video here. You can literally grab
it for free. So people get a little bit
confused. I just wanted to explain where
that that is so you can come and grab it
there. Now what this design lip does, it
helps us basically basically inspire and
get the style that we want to using some
really cool techniques. All you're going
to do is copy it all before if you
haven't come back over to Claude, drop
it in, and then let Claude work its
magic. And side note, by the way, you
can actually do all this in Room if you
wanted to. If you click on publish at
the top left, it kind of functions as a
full CRM system. So if you look at the
one that I built earlier, for example,
the roofing code website, you can see
you can build everything. So, one of the
big things that people struggle with is
a CMS. So, it's the exact same thing.
You've got the brief it builds out for
you, which is really awesome. You get
the full site map here. You get the
wireframes as well, which you can edit
in a million different ways. It's super
intuitive. And then you've got the
designs that you can play around with.
Then in the top right, when you're done
with it, you can actually publish it
like so in a click. And then you've got
this continue and you can view it in a
new window and have a great time doing
it. What is really cool just very
quickly if you're doing it here if you
click on for example library you can see
the images you've got styling over here
but if you click on this little settings
here you can edit the pages like so you
can see the meta title meta description
it's just it's an easy in the box way if
you wanted to go ahead and do that but
we're going to do now is come back over
to Claude and see what it built for us
but Claude is not going to be able to
get us a beautiful website that looks
anything like this unless we give it the
ability to generate beautiful images
with the latest models. How do we do
that? Well, the one that we're going to
be using here is Higsfield. I use this
all the time. All the images you see in
my websites, presentations. I use this.
The really cool thing about this is we
can actually connect this to Claude so
easily. All you're going to do, and I'll
put a link down below. So, you can click
it and just grab you can screenshot this
if you want to or just grab the URL.
I'll just give it the URL I post down
below. Now, what we can do with this is
build images in the best models, best
videos. But effectively what's really
cool about it once you screenshot this
will copy the link. You just let Claude
know hey I want you to connect to the
Higsfield CLI so we can create beautiful
images and videos. Here's the link just
like that and it'll open you up in a new
browser. You sign in and then you're
ready and able to make the magic happen.
And when I tell you that using
Hakesfield on websites isn't just about
3D animations. You can literally build
things that look spectacular stuff that
you wouldn't even really think. And I'll
show you exactly what I mean in a
minute. So then we have this beautiful
website which again we built the
structure. This is the step that
everyone misses guys building out the
site map and the structure because one
pages are cool but no one just buys a
page right they need buttons to click on
if you're selling this for a roofing
company if you're selling this to any
business at all. They need to have this
sort of stuff locked down which is
great. We got that structure. We got the
best design system. We got the images
and videos and then this is what we've
got from that. It's built as a logo,
which is awesome. And again, one of the
great reasons why we bring in Hicksville
because we can just build these logos as
we go if the client doesn't have it. And
you'll notice it also copies the exact
style here with the green and the black,
which is what we wanted to be inspired
by. And we've got that, which is
awesome. So then we can come down and
have a look. This is a nice thing. We've
got this beautiful animation. We've got
the companies that we're working with.
Nice bit of animation here, which is
awesome. And in fact, what's really
cool, you can see as you refresh it,
these animations pop up. Build the same
thing. That's really crisp. And then
we've got these different businesses we
work with. Anthropic, Slack. Obviously,
these are examples. I don't know if
Stripe is paying us to do the roofs.
Well, at Ridgeline, guys, they are at
Ridgeline. We work with the best AI
companies ever to give them the best
roof. Don't you ever forget our roof
abilities. Loved by your favorite
companies. This this is really crisp,
guys. Like, this is just the design on
this is fantastic. And look at the
adherence, by the way. Look at the
adherence to some of the features here.
So, if you can come down and see
actually as it scrolls down, look at the
scrollability at the bottom of this. You
see this? I just love how it's kind of
like done its own thing, but kind of
understood why that looks good and why
that's so crisp. I mean, it's just such
a beautiful design. Then you can come
back. We've got this here. Find out what
is actually wrong with your website. And
then we've got all this stuff here. But
it doesn't just stop there. Now, we've
actually got the website. So, we've got
different pages and stuff that we can
play around with. So, we can click on
things like services and about us and
build these pages out. and it's just got
the whole site map that's been developed
now by using these tools. Now, believe
it or not, this is just the foundation.
Level three is where we take it to a new
level. Now, to reiterate, we've got the
site map. We use Room to get basically
one brief in. We got site maps,
wireframes, which is cool now because if
we ever want to build out the website,
we can do it in one location, which is
super handy. These are humanmade
components. They're not necessarily AI
generated, which is awesome, and it's
going to help us have a really
consistent style with all the beautiful
websites that we build on. Level three
is the scroll stopper. You know, this is
a classic example. I built this again
using Hixold video generation. It's
beautiful. It's a showstopper, but
everyone thinks of just the website, but
there's so many different ways that you
can actually create attention,
especially if you want to drive lots of
conversions, and these do convert. They
are beautiful, but there's many ways, as
they say, to skin a cat. So, for
example, if you come over to a website
that I'm in love with recently, which is
save with two E, many E. You can see
these beautiful designs. But what's
really cool is you can search for
inspiration. So, I could come down and
like I've said before, I might say
dashboard UI. So, let's say that we're
building out a dashboard together,
right? And we want some inspiration. You
you can look at Pinterest, but
everybody's on Pinterest. Although
Pinterest is cool to be fair, you can
find beautiful things. Let's say I want
to have a sign up form, right? Maybe we
want to add something interactive to our
roofing website essentially so that they
give their information, but then what if
we could have a beautiful, you know, get
them a quote, some kind of lead magnet.
Well, we can find beautiful designs that
were inspired by one such one that I
found that looked amazing was this one.
But what's the problem with this, Jack?
The problem with this is this is not a
component. This is not a UI thing that
we can just grab. We need to literally
basically create this, but in the style
for our own website. So, all we're going
to do is we're going to copy this image
like so and head over to Claude. And
just like before, you're going to do
forward slash. You type in design loop.
And essentially, you're going to come
down and say, "Hey there, I want you to
make a roofing version of this." And
what I would like you to do is enable
them to upload an image of the roof,
answer a few questions, and then I want
a beautiful Siri like animation to play
and then actually show what the price is
for them, and we can capture that
information. Okay, give it that prompt,
drop it in the image, and then let's go
find a Siri type animation. And just
like that, guys, I've got one here. And
that looks freaking gorgeous. I like
that. I want to what? I don't know what
that is selling, but I want to buy that
right now. So, I'm going to come down.
I'm just going to download this as a
kind of video overview suggestion for
Claude to use. And just like this, guys,
we now have a free quote for your roof,
which is cool. So, we can upload an
image if you want to. Got a postcode.
We'll just check out what it looks like.
Click on get my price. And then here we
go. We got our animation. It's checking
pitch and tiles, price of materials.
Almost there. having a look around. I
mean, you can just see how fun this is,
right? Bam. £7,150.
And then it's got some different things
here for like reviews and you can book
the free survey. So freaking cool. I
mean, when you have the right skills,
you can pay the bills, as they say. No
one said I'm not saying I'm a rapid just
cuz I'm wearing this like funky jumper,
but you get the idea. Now, this didn't
exist until we built it. One of the
reasons why this is so cool, by the way,
is like at the bottom of the image, you
can see I hold it here. It's got white.
Now, ideally, these drops would have
finished so it looks like a true blend
in, but it's kind of phased out a little
bit. So, it just gives it that nice kind
of beautiful blend. And that's awesome.
I get my quote. It's done some cool AI
analysis, which we can bake in the
website. I'm using various different
like skills which are quite easy. And
then we can just add this to the
website. And by the way, if this sounds
like I'm speaking in design Spanish, I'm
going to put a link down below for my
full core code master class that will
take you through foundations. It will
take you through building websites from
zero to deploying them, power features,
memory systems, Hermes agent, apps,
building anything, monetizing this
stuff, and I'll also show you the full
and beautiful Claude code operating
system that has all the bells and
whistles, the memory systems, the cost
saving, the design OS, a million other
different things that you definitely
want to have a look at if you want to
level up and get light years ahead of
everybody else. It's not fair on your
competitors. I will say that much. It's
not going to be fair on your
competitors, so just bear that in mind.
Now, we've got these scroll stoppers,
which is awesome. But it doesn't just
stop that. We can take this much
further. What does that look like at
level four, Jack? Well, level four
itself, and I'm going to show you all
these things integrated into the website
in a second once we've added a few of
the other bells and whistles, and you'll
see what I mean when I say that. Level
four realistically, is understanding
that 60% of traffic at least actually is
on our phones. I should had my phone out
earlier before I said that. A lot of
people are on their phones. They're not
necessarily always sat down at a
desktop, but yet most content always
focuses on the screen. And I'm guilty of
that to be fair to some extent as well
because it's just easy to show. But what
we need to do is mobile optimize our
website. Now, how do you mobile optimize
a website? Well, to be honest with you,
there are loads of skills and I'll I'll
put a link down below in the post. But
honestly, you can head over to Claude
and say, "Hey, I want you to mobile
optimize this website. go out and find
for me the most proficient, well-reed
repos that have been battle tested that
will make sure that it follows all of
the best mobile design principles. And
I'll put a link down below for my
favorite. And essentially, once you've
done that, call to go ahead and it'll
mobile optimize it. Well, how do we know
that? Well, we can just do this. Look at
it. This is really cool. You can see how
at every frame rate it makes a
difference. Now, believe it or not, it
did it did not look like this initially.
I had to do this, but look at this,
guys. You can come down and see that. We
need to just uh fix that a little bit.
As you can see, it's not perfect, but
look at this. It's a website you can
actually use and understand on mobile.
And again, I can still scroll through
these and it's added these different
elements in. I think this is great that
it's just Look at this, guys. That's
crazy because remember, most of your
traffic is going to be on mobile. And a
lot of times you go to mobile, they've
never optimized it for it. You can't
even read the actual website itself.
It's even got this nice hamburger thing
in. You must mobile optimize your
website. In fact, most people and when I
did my last tech startup, which by the
way, if you are new, I built and sold my
last tech startup with like a gazillion
customers and now I'm building my own AI
startup here and I was really big on SEO
and building out websites. And honestly,
we'd start off with the mobile first and
then work backwards to get to the actual
full desktop version. And there is no
substitute, but to actually going
through the mobile yourself. Claude can
do loads of checks using the Reaper that
I'll share down below uh in the skills
section, but ultimately speaking, you
want to go through the website yourself
and check it out. and we got this
beautiful email address and we're having
a great time. But then that takes us on
to the biggest problem of this video so
far and that is what I call the fight
against the AI slop monster. I invite
you to join me. I am I'm good against AI
slot but I am one man and I I I would
like a team. Now what do we call the
dlopification? What do I mean by that? I
mean that AI itself, if you ever look at
it, has like a really standard way of
presenting itself. It's so obvious that
something's written by AI. And as I
showed on my other videos, I built this
copy system which is really cool and I
encourage you to look at something like
this because I built this inside my
community because I got this question
all the time. Effectively, you can just
grab information from the best GitHub
repos which are the slopification and it
basically takes all the classic signs of
AI writing like Wikipedia for example
and it just like runs it all through
that. You can run it through GPT 5.6 as
well to make it sound way more human
because most websites these days are
written by Claude, hence why they all
sound the same. Um, and you can just
identify all these classic things that
AI does. And then it's underpinned by
some core psychology. One of the best
psychological principles in building
anything is this idea of don't make me
think. The idea essentially being that
when people don't read websites, they
browse them. What do I mean by that? I
mean, I need to be able to glance at it
and understand what the website is
about. You know, don't take anybody's
time for granted. Don't just assume that
that, you know, you have to earn their
time. And if I have to invest a minute
to understand what your website is
about, it's too much. It's way too much.
So general idea, use the system two
cognition. Don't make me think. Sorry,
the system one cognition. Just make it
super easy. You want to name the pain.
And again, the other thing you want to
do is run this through loads of key
marketing and psychological and sales
things. Um, for example, the classic
example I always give here, instead of
get started, start free. Instead of the
fun way to learn AI, everyone uses AI.
So at level five, you want to do a
delopification of everything. So, and my
website system brings up some copy here.
So, check this out. Again, it just runs
through everything. So, signs of AI
writing. Look at this. Trusted,
reliable, and built to last. Six nails
per shingle. Every shingle. How cool is
that? I mean, it's like it's it's the
same thing, but it's just giving a
practical example. And these are just,
you know, the the rules and principles
apply to this website. Not just a roof,
but peace of mind. Guys, how many let me
down below in the comment section could
tell that that was written by if you saw
that you'd be like, "Dude, which AI
person has written that a written scope
and a fixed number before anyone climbs
the ladder?" Yeah, obviously that just
sounds so much better. Elevated verbs
instead of we leverage industryleading
materials to deliver unparalleled
protection. We source materials from
manufacturers who test for wind, hail,
and sun.
Leverage deliver. It's like it's
awesome, guys. Empty superlatives, the
area's most trusted roofing experts. No
roofing and only roofing since 2020
2001.
M dash pileup. Our team trained,
certified and local is ready to help. 38
on the crew factory trained for every
material we install.
Which one, genuinely speaking, are you
going to click on and be like, obviously
that's better. Loved by 10,000 happy
homeowners, project names and
photography are placeholders. Swapping
your own jobs before this goes live.
Yeah. Okay. That one's just telling me
that like I built placeholders, so that
one's like not a good idea, but you get
the idea. and you get this full
breakdown explaining everything, the
principles, stuff like that. We have to
deiify our entire website such that it
actually just reads like a human wrote
it because I will tell you this that
what people aren't telling you is the
fact that people can smell AI websites
coming from 6 milesi away unless you
unpin these issues unless you make it
non-mobile optimized, unless you make it
mobile optimized and you're actually
kind of like attacking the slop issue
which these skills do. But now we've
solved some of the text. We move on to
level six. Now level six is an
interesting one and it's icons and
showstoppers. What do I mean by that?
Now this is what I call UI sniping. And
I love UI sniping. Now UI sniping is the
idea that we can find any UI component
that we like and bring it over. Reloom
itself is building out a really cool
freaking library of stuff that you can
just go ahead and grab, which is decent.
So cool advantage being it's built by
designers. Another good example of this
is 21st.dev dev where you can basically
find different things like libraries,
backgrounds, borders, whatever it is.
Find stuff that you like and you can
basically bring them over. Obviously, if
you got really, it's super handsy going
do that as well. I know that the guys
over there are building out all their
stuff, which is really freaking cool. If
you've got the real MCP, you can just
ask it or if you're grabbing it from a
different website like 21st.dev, you can
come down and literally just copy the
code and say you want this, for example,
this design, which looks cool. You just
copy the code, head over to Claude and
say, "Hey, add this to my website." And
then when I come back over the website,
you can see I added these things in
here. Look at this. booked in a week.
And look at this. I'll hover over. I can
see these customers. 4,800 roofs kept
dry. And again, it's just nice little
credibility cuz it's just like, how can
you show that you're legitimate? Cuz
that's one of the questions people have,
right? You can see I hover over and it's
got that stuff here fully integrated
into the website and you can move it in
any direction that you like. And of
course, you can also use icons. I'm a
really big fan of icons. Um, there's
different ones like icons 8, flat icon,
Icon Scout, loads of different ones.
Check them all out. I think the one I'm
using right now is flat icon. Again,
like not sponsored by them or anything
like that. I just tell you like I just
think they're pretty cool. Basically,
you can come down and get like different
styles. So, if you're doing a kind of
new age cool vibe, younger demographic
like um I'd say millennial or like Gen Z
or below, you may want to use cool
graphics and you can just like get loads
of different styles, they it only costs
like $10 to 12 to, you know, be on one
of these websites. And effectively, once
you're on there, you can just use those
icons u based on the license you've got.
Again, the I don't know these guys. I'm
not sponsored by these guys. I'm just
telling you like it's something you can
do to just make it look a little bit
kind of fresh and stuff if that if that
fits your design and vibe. But if not,
you can just UI sty and make it look
amazing. But then that does bring us
very nicely onto level seven. Now level
seven is something that a lot of people
miss and that is the SEOification of
your website. I know we have loads of
different skills on GitHub. I like
Claude SEO. It's quite nice. You can see
this one here. Um it's fairly well
reviewed. It's got this I think this
guy's a content creator as well. So
shout out to this guy. But effectively
SEO nerds, I call them nerds. Um I hope
they don't mind if they love SEO. They
basically codify it and you can build
out systems that do stuff like this to
really help you kind of like run through
your website. So what we do is we head
over to Claude and then you say, "Hey, I
want you to go ahead and find for me the
best SEO design strategies that exist on
the internet and I want you to take a
look at this SEO repo and I want you to
build a checklist and a strategy for my
website. The the things that I can rank
for. Here are some of the keywords that
I want to rank for. here's the kind of
intent that I want to do and I want you
to question me on my customer so that we
together can find out the longtail
intention words, the short intention
words and I want you to rank those based
on um basically volume and also
difficulty. And from that we're going to
build up an SEO strategy, a content road
map, and we're going to find SEO
suggestions for our own website. And
once you do that, you're going to find a
page that looks a little bit something
like this. This is an exercise I did
recently for Glider, my speech to text
startups. how I'm able to talk to
things. And I mean, just look at the
detail of this, guys. Like speech to
text, how many people search it, the
demand index, how hard is it? And it
just finds those nice um kind of sweet
spots. Again, got 28 keywords that we
should rank for. Longtail stuff like
Whisper Flow alternative. Um every other
it's just really, really helpful. And
you can use this to build out a content
strategy. I mean, this is just literally
the stuff that I'm doing in my own tech
startup right now. And you can use AI to
do this in any of your websites or
systems. And then to post it, you just
need to basically tell Claude to upload
this to GitHub in a private repo. I've
got full tutorials on the channel. I'll
put links somewhere to show you the
process. And then you can run the entire
thing from Versel. Versel hosts
everything. It even hosts many of the
websites that I show you on this
channel. Super duper easy to set up.
Explain to Claude and it will explain it
to you step by step. But this does bring
us on to a problem and that's the fact
that these design skills are handy and
they do help us build beautiful websites
that sell. But the truth is, if you
don't have your own design operating
system, you're leaving way too many
hours and productivity and value on the
table. Which is why the next thing that
we need to do is learn how to set one of
these up, which we're going to do in
this video right